Hey everyone! Have you ever felt confused and overwhelmed
not being able to find those pesky deleted or modified files on the computer? Well, fear no more cause AEAS is here to help!
So, what's AEAS?
It's an application that helps e-forensic investigators get their work done!
Basically, the e-forensic investigators seize necessary evidence (i.e. the system), acquires the data (i.e. e-forensic image),
analyses it and reports their findings of deleted and modified files with necessary details.
And our program will do the final two steps for them, simplifying and speeding up the entire process!
Lets take a look at some existing software.
So, what’s the problem with all of these?
There are three key issues are common in existing solutions.
They have a steep learning curve. You need to already understand the specific software to use it.
As shown on the previous slide, a lot of information is displayed all at once, and this can be overwhelming.
Some common processes require clicking through countless unnecessary wizards and dialogs, which is inefficient.
Our team has been collaborating with our client, Bad Security Incorporated.
This collaboration allows our team to explore and understand the problem and solution space of the project.
We spent a lot of time defining the problem space – drilling down into industry weak points to gleam key areas for improvement.
From there, we designed the application by prioritizing the three design principles on the slide.
Make it simple, make it smooth, and make it sleek.
Let’s see these design principles in action.
A simple, sleek user-friendly interface, and the whole process from project start to report generation takes only 8 seconds.
And here are some of the things that AEAS will put into the report.
The key statistics are hard disk information, a list of detected files, results from a string keyword search,
and a timeline of file modifications performed on the machine.
AEAS will leverage tried and tested tools, to ensure the integrity of data analysis.
AEAS will be able to identify suspicious files, whether they have been deleted, obfuscated or unallocated.
Modern frameworks such as react and electron allow for a clean application that is user friendly and portable.
AEAS will produce reports on its findings for expert forensic specialist
to quickly get informed for further investigatory decision making.
This will be provided as a software package built on and for open source technologies.
What does the future hold for the AEAS team?
We will use an agile inspired work process to allow us to adapt our development to the feedback we get as we:
Prototype, Polish, Test, and engage end users.
The AEAS team is confident that we will be able to deliver a high quality application that streamlines
and kickstarts the forensic process, allowing investigators to focus more on what is important.